<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christian Y. Robert | ASTeRISK</title>
    <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/author/christian-y.-robert/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/author/christian-y.-robert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Christian Y. Robert</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/media/icon_hu31e1642898cd664f469967b29f567aa2_42147_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Christian Y. Robert</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/author/christian-y.-robert/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-sharing rules and their properties, with applications to peer-to-peer insurance</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/dhaene_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/dhaene_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper offers a systematic treatment of risk-sharing rules for insurance losses, based on a list of relevant properties. A number of candidate risk-sharing rules are considered, including the conditional mean risk-sharing rule proposed in Denuit and Dhaene (2012) and the newly introduced quantile risk-sharing rule. Their compliance with the proposed properties is established. Then, methods for building new risk-sharing rules are discussed. The results derived in this paper are shown to be helpful in the development of peer-to-peer insurance (or crowdsurance), as well as to manage contingent risk funds where a given budget is distributed among claimants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality credits within large survivor funds</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/denuit1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/denuit1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survivor funds are financial arrangements where participants agree to share the proceeds of a collective investment pool in a pre-described way depending on their survival. This offers investors a way to benefit from mortality credits, boosting financial returns. Following Denuit (2019), participants are assumed to adopt the conditional mean risk sharing rule introduced in Denuit and Dhaene (2012) to assess their respective shares in mortality credits. This paper considers the case of a large pool and studies the asymptotic behavior of mortality credits. A law of large numbers and a central-limit theorem are established, as well as simple approximations for a sufficiently large number of participants. A risk transfer network structure is also proposed to allow participants to restrict sharing to a community of individuals with whom they are connected. Lifelong incomes can be obtained by combining investments in survivor funds over consecutive periods, offering an alternative to modern tontines or pooled annuity funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
