<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASTeRISK</title>
    <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ASTeRISK</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/media/icon_hu31e1642898cd664f469967b29f567aa2_42147_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>ASTeRISK</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations and applications of decentralized risk sharing</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/workshop_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/workshop_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 18-19, 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KU Leuven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&lt;/a&gt;.
This initiative is sponsered by the ASTeRISK project. The workshop relates to the third research line of the ASTeRISK project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risk-sharing mechanisms have been studied for decades in the actuarial literature, starting with the pioneering work of Karl Borch who investigated equilibrium in a reinsurance market in the early 1960s. Decentralized risk-sharing refers to risk-sharing mechanisms under which the participants in a pool decide to share their risks among each other in such a way that the sum all losses paid from the pool matches the sum of the contributions paid by the participants.  As mentioned above, investigating  how to determine &amp;lsquo;fair&amp;rsquo; contributions in a decentralized risk-sharing problem is an old research problem in the actuarial and risk-sharing literature. The recent interest in a sharing economy, collaborative consumption and decentralized finance, together with recent advances in technology have led to a renewed academic interest in decentralized risk-sharing mechanisms. Moreover, in practice, peer-to-peer (P2P) or collaborative insurance revives early forms of mutual insurance, where the contributions of the many are used to cover the misfortunes of the few, while keeping insurer’s experience in claim settlement and risk-bearing capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking into account these new practical and theoretical evolutions, we have decided to launch an academic forum for research on decentralized risk-sharing and its applications. FADeRiS-2023 is the first of (hopefully) a series of workshops, with the goal of bringing together researchers active in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure and honor to dedicate this first FADeRiS workshop held at KU Leuven to prof. dr. Marc Goovaerts, one of the most brilliant actuarial researchers of his generation and a great mentor for many Belgian and Dutch actuaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan, Mario, and Michel (the organizers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prize-Winning Paper Tackles Machine Learning Actuarial Models</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/article_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/article_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article in The Actuary Magazine on the award winning paper “Boosting Insights in Insurance Tariff Plans with Tree-Based Machine Learning Methods,” authored by Roel Henckaerts, Marie-Pier Côté, Katrien Antonio and Roel Verbelen. This paper is related to the first and second research line of the ASTeRISK project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published April, 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theactuarymagazine.org/prize-winning-paper-tackles-machine-learning-actuarial-models/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.theactuarymagazine.org/prize-winning-paper-tackles-machine-learning-actuarial-models/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract-from-the-article&#34;&gt;Abstract from the article:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of machine learning (ML) are widespread. It can help organizations get the most out of raw data, and its applications hold the promise of improving lives. The actuarial profession shares in the potential power of ML, but new technologies can be disruptive. ML actuarial models, for example, can be so complex they lack transparency, threatening to weaken consumers’ trust and raise regulators’ suspicions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timely topic of actuarial ML was the focus of a North American Actuarial Journal (NAAJ) article that was chosen as the best in 2021. This prize-winning paper looks inside ML pricing models to understand how they work and explore real-world applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating function method for the efficient computation of expected allocations</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 14, 2022, 12h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KU Leuven, FEB, HOGS 01.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a risk portfolio with aggregate loss random variable S=X1+⋯+Xn defined as the sum of the n individual losses X1,…,Xn. The expected allocation, E[Xi×1{S=k}], for i=1,…,n and k∈N, is a vital quantity for risk allocation and risk-sharing. For example, one uses this value to compute peer-to-peer contributions under the conditional mean risk-sharing rule and capital allocated to a line of business under the Euler risk allocation paradigm. This paper introduces an ordinary generating function for expected allocations, a power series representation of the expected allocation of an individual risk given the total risks in the portfolio when all risks are discrete. First, we provide a simple relationship between the ordinary generating function for expected allocations and the probability generating function. Then, leveraging properties of ordinary generating functions, we reveal new theoretical results on closed-formed solutions to risk allocation problems, especially when dealing with Katz or compound Katz distributions. Then, we present an efficient algorithm to recover the expected allocations using the fast Fourier transform, providing a new practical tool to compute expected allocations quickly. The latter approach is exceptionally efficient for a portfolio of independent risks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Tontines &amp; Modern Problems</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 18, 2022, 12h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KU Leuven, FEB, HOGM 01.74&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the mid-18th to the late 19th century, tontine schemes were one of the most popular investment products and methods of raising economic capital for long-term projects. But by the early 20th century they had fallen into disrepute, outlawed in many legal jurisdictions and forgotten other than in crime novels and works of fiction. Recently though, academics and scholars have developed a renewed interest in tontine-related longevity pooling schemes with over 100 scientific articles (and counting) published on the topic in the early decades of the 21st century. Then, in the fall of 2022 a Canadian investment company was granted authorisation by regulators to launch a modern version of the tontine, partially encouraged by the above noted scientific research. Motivated by all this activity the 75-minute presentation will review some of the colourful history and literature (1/3), explain the actuarial and financial characteristics of the “modern” structure (1/3) and then focus on some “open” mathematical problems stimulated by recent tontine design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Risk Assessment for Capital Management</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;June 2, 2022, 11h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KU Leuven, FEB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber risk is an omnipresent risk in the increasingly digitized world that is known to be difficult to quantify and assess. Despite the fact that cyber risk shows distinct characteristics from conventional risks, most existing models for cyber risk in the insurance literature have been purely based on frequency-severity analysis, which was developed for classical property and casualty risks. In contrast, the cybersecurity engineering literature employs different approaches, under which cyber incidents are viewed as threats or hacker attacks acting on a particular set of vulnerabilities. There appears a gap in cyber risk modeling between engineering and insurance literature. This paper presents a novel model to capture this unique dynamics of cyber risk known from engineering and to model loss distributions based on industry loss data and a particular company&amp;rsquo;s cybersecurity profile. The analysis leads to a new tool for allocating resources of the company between cybersecurity investments and loss-absorbing reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer-to-peer Multi-Risk Insurance and Mutual Aid</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/seminar_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 16, 2022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KU Leuven, FEB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) insurance is a decentralized network in which participants pool their resources together to 
compensate those who suffer losses. The rise of P2P insurance in Western countries, such as Friendsurance and Lemonade, has been viewed a disruptor to the traditional insurance industry in the same way Uber is to the taxi industry. A similar business model of mutual aid, such as Xiang Hu Bao, has become popular in the East, which provides financial support to those in needs and spreads the cost among all participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fast-changing landscape in this field, there has been scarce literature on the theoretical underpinning of P2P insurance and mutual aid. This paper presents the first effort to build a unified framework to quantify and assess the exchange of risks in a network of participants from different risk classes. Under this framework, the paper aims to address several essential research questions including the fair exchange of heterogeneous risks and the optimality of algorithmic designs under various criteria. The modeling of multi-risk exchange is done with a P2P network structures. We show that not only these network structures can be used to explain the current practice in the industry but also provide new tools to develop better designs. The paper concludes with a comparison of traditional insurance and P2P risk sharing from the standpoint of stability and cost reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hierarchical reserving model for reported non-life insurance claims</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/paper1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional non-life reserving models largely neglect the vast amount of information collected over the lifetime of a claim. This information includes covariates describing the policy, claim cause as well as the detailed history collected during a claim&amp;rsquo;s development over time. We present the hierarchical reserving model as a modular framework for integrating a claim&amp;rsquo;s history and claim-specific covariates into the development process. Hierarchical reserving models decompose the joint likelihood of the development process over time. Moreover, they are tailored to the portfolio at hand by adding a layer to the model for each of the events registered during the development of a claim (e.g. settlement, payment). Layers are modelled with statistical learning (e.g. generalized linear models) or machine learning methods (e.g. gradient boosting machines) and use claim-specific covariates. As a result of its flexibility, this framework incorporates many existing reserving models, ranging from aggregate models designed for run-off triangles to individual models using claim-specific covariates. This connection allows us to develop a data-driven strategy for choosing between aggregate and individual reserving; an important decision for reserving practitioners. We illustrate our method with a case study on a real insurance data set and deduce new insights in the covariates driving the development of claims. Moreover, we evaluate the method&amp;rsquo;s performance on a large number of simulated portfolios representing several realistic development scenarios and demonstrate the flexibility and robustness of the hierarchical reserving model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-sharing rules and their properties, with applications to peer-to-peer insurance</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/dhaene_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/dhaene_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper offers a systematic treatment of risk-sharing rules for insurance losses, based on a list of relevant properties. A number of candidate risk-sharing rules are considered, including the conditional mean risk-sharing rule proposed in Denuit and Dhaene (2012) and the newly introduced quantile risk-sharing rule. Their compliance with the proposed properties is established. Then, methods for building new risk-sharing rules are discussed. The results derived in this paper are shown to be helpful in the development of peer-to-peer insurance (or crowdsurance), as well as to manage contingent risk funds where a given budget is distributed among claimants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Researchers</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/vacancies/phd_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/vacancies/phd_call/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-asterisk-team-welcomes-applications-for-phd-positions-within-each-of-the-projects-research-lines&#34;&gt;The ASTeRISK team welcomes applications for PhD positions within each of the project’s research lines.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates should hold an MSc degree in e.g. statistics, mathematics, computer science, actuarial sciences, data science or similar. The PhD student will join a vibrant community of young researchers, supervised by a team of senior researchers at the forefront of the international research landscape in both actuarial, statistics and biostatistics research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positions will either be based at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://feb.kuleuven.be&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Faculty of Economics and Business at KU Leuven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uclouvain.be/en/research-institutes/lidam/isba&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences at UCLouvain&lt;/a&gt;, or both (leading to a joint PhD degree from both institutes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interested-in-joining-us&#34;&gt;Interested in joining us?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please use &lt;a href=&#34;https://uclouvain.be/fr/instituts-recherche/lidam/isba/application-form-eos-researcher.html&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the application form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For questions about the application, please contact the PI&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katrien Antonio: katrien[dot]antonio[at]kuleuven.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donatien Hainaut: donatien[dot]hainaut[at]uclouvain.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Researchers</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/vacancies/postdoc_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/vacancies/postdoc_call/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-asterisk-team-welcomes-applications-for-2-year-full-time-postdoctoral-positions-within-each-of-the-projects-research-lines&#34;&gt;The ASTeRISK team welcomes applications for 2-year full time postdoctoral positions within each of the project’s research lines.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are particularly looking for expertise related (but not limited) to: joint models, survival models, risk measures, peer-to-peer insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The postdoc will take an active role in the development of the ASTeRISK research lines and the management of the project, as a linking pin between the young researchers and the team of coPIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positions will either be based at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://feb.kuleuven.be&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Faculty of Economics and Business at KU Leuven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uclouvain.be/en/research-institutes/lidam/isba&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences at UCLouvain&lt;/a&gt;, or both (leading to a joint PhD degree from both institutes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interested-in-joining-us&#34;&gt;Interested in joining us?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please use &lt;a href=&#34;https://uclouvain.be/fr/instituts-recherche/lidam/isba/application-form-eos-researcher.html&#34;  style=&#34;color:#52BDEC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the application form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For questions about the application, please contact the PI&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katrien Antonio: katrien[dot]antonio[at]kuleuven.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donatien Hainaut: donatien[dot]hainaut[at]uclouvain.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project and website launch</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/sitelaunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/ast_event/sitelaunch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-and-location&#34;&gt;Time and location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 28, 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eos-asterisk.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.eos-asterisk.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch of the ASTeRISK project and website&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality credits within large survivor funds</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/denuit1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/publication/denuit1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;just&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survivor funds are financial arrangements where participants agree to share the proceeds of a collective investment pool in a pre-described way depending on their survival. This offers investors a way to benefit from mortality credits, boosting financial returns. Following Denuit (2019), participants are assumed to adopt the conditional mean risk sharing rule introduced in Denuit and Dhaene (2012) to assess their respective shares in mortality credits. This paper considers the case of a large pool and studies the asymptotic behavior of mortality credits. A law of large numbers and a central-limit theorem are established, as well as simple approximations for a sufficiently large number of participants. A risk transfer network structure is also proposed to allow participants to restrict sharing to a community of individuals with whom they are connected. Lifelong incomes can be obtained by combining investments in survivor funds over consecutive periods, offering an alternative to modern tontines or pooled annuity funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/privacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eos-asterisk.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
